# **Richard Enlow**

Design Technologist (Visual / UX / Web)

richardenlow@gmail.com

# Summary

I specialize in Visual Design and User Experience Design, working with a broad set of skills and tools. My passion is design direction, creative concepting, and the design of desktop and mobile websites.

I believe in putting people at the heart of the design process, from conception to execution. By recognizing user goals and measuring against those goals, I am able to deliver top-notch, highly-accessible designs that both look great and are easy to use.

In my spare time, you can find me at rock or electronica shows (I'm a huge music fan), chaperoning my dog (she's a party animal! http://www.instagram.com/ohiathedog), and exploring an ever-growing collection of interests.

Over the past year I've found I have a knack for taking my designs and turning them into code. I am really excited to learn more!

# Skills & Expertise

**Graphic Design Email Marketing** 

**SEO** 

Illustrator

**Typography** 

**User Interface Design** 

**Photoshop** 

Web Design

**User Experience Design** 

**Rapid Prototyping** 

**User Research** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

CSS3

HTML5

**jQuery** 

Sass

Git

**Product Management** 

**CSS** 

**Human Computer Interaction** 

**Design Direction** 

**Mobile Design** 

**JavaScript** 

# Responsive Design Layout

# Experience

# Design Co-Founder at Amoeba Consulting, LLC

October 2012 - Present (10 months)

I play a key design role throughout a client's product development cycle from initial rapid-prototyping through pixel-perfect implementation. By using best-practices in UX, UI, and Visual Design and cutting-edge front-end implementation using HTML5, CSS3, and JS -- I help clients to build out their products. By conceptualizing and testing the interaction between users and products I help them to make products users don't have to think about.

#### Clients Include:

- The Mozilla Foundation
- SF New Tech A platform for young startups and established companies alike, to show off what they've been working on
- Buzzstarter A web app that engages users by incentivizing their "buzz"
- VULUME A project collaboration, sharing, and discovery tool for the Built Environment
- TCS Center Consumer facing commerce site
- Change.org Petition landing page with integrated Twilio API for users to contact your representative
- Exumit An anonymous review site for sales professionals
- BitCartel's Comic Book Lover Enables comic fans to easily view, collect, and organise digital comics
- Among others

#### Design Contractor at re: Design

January 2007 - Present (6 years 7 months)

As a contract designer, worked on a variety of projects for organizations on both paid and on a pro-bono basis including:

Oxford University Press, Incloud Counsel, Hack The Future, San Francisco Community Clinics Consortium, Kapoosh!, Athletes' Performance, Firefighter Combat Challenge, Kay Van Norman, Finish Line Ink, ICI Paints, Creative Concepts, Cendant Corporation, Mervyns, Communications Services for the Deaf, Alibaba Group, Language Town – Beijing, Zhong Jia Display, Science of Sounds, SPCA, C.I.T., New Barbary Coast Distribution, PsychedelicSF.org, among others.

#### Senior Designer - Web and Print at TI Media

February 2010 - November 2012 (2 years 10 months)

Created and maintained content for web and email marketing for mid-sized multinational with locations in San Francisco, New York, London, and Paris. Established and maintained consistent style across multiple departments. Design lead on internal company sites as well as multiple external websites. As design lead on online marketing efforts I overhauled the company's email marketing presence, increasing reach and click

through rate. Created the visual identity for all consumer products recognized internationally, including a Best Packaging Design award two years consecutively.

# Project Manager - Market Research at FSC Group

September 2009 - April 2010 (8 months)

Operational role for a tier one market research firm, specializing in market research methods. Responsible for support and the development of infrastructure and systems to provide smooth and efficient operations inline with organizational needs. Provided support to ensure that the organization's strategic plan and projects were effectively implemented.

### Senior Designer - Web and Print at Keiser Corporation

September 2005 - January 2009 (3 years 5 months)

Designed a variety of global marketing for print, multimedia, web, advertising, promotional, and customer support. Coordinated countless projects; from initial creation, vendor acquisitions, print specification, prepress preparation, production, to distribution.

Established and evolved Keiser's design and branding; to increase market position, generate leads and initiate sales.

# Education

# **General Assembly**

Front-End Web Development, 2013

Activities and Societies: Selected for a full scholarship from the school.

#### C.I.T.

Design - Graphic and Web, 2005

Activities and Societies: Founders Award, Dean's List

#### **Hasso Plattner - Institute of Design at Stanford (d.school)**

Design Thinking Action Lab, 2013

### Courses

#### **Independent Coursework**

Guiding UX Principles Extended

**Usability Research** 

Introduction to Public Speaking

#### Adobe PDF Workflows

#### Adobe Creative Suite Advanced

#### HackDesign

### Honors and Awards

# **Award Winner - Packaging Category**

SMB-Berlin

November 2012

#### **Award Winner - Packaging Category**

SMB-Berlin

October 2011

#### **Excellence in Print Award**

Print Industries Association June 2009

#### iF Design Award

iF Industrie Forum Design January 2009

#### **Design Excellence Award**

**ISDA** 

April 2008

#### **Eagle Scout**

Boy Scouts of America 1997

# Volunteer Experience

### Designer and Design Instruction Lead at Hack the Future

November 2012 - Present (9 months)

I'm working to get kids excited about design, design thinking, and process!

### **Graphic Designer at Taproot Foundation**

August 2011 - Present (2 years)

Taproot is a nonprofit organization that makes business talent available to organizations working to improve society.

#### Volunteer at Animal Rescue Ecuador

# August 2011 - November 2011 (4 months)

Lived and worked in the Amazon Basin of Ecuador. Responsible for care of animals, threat reduction and community outreach.

# **Richard Enlow**

Design Technologist (Visual / UX / Web)

richardenlow@gmail.com



Contact Richard on LinkedIn